Guide to the William R. K. Young and Morgan A. Gunst correspondence, 1909-1940 M0008
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William R. K. Young and Morgan A. Gunst correspondence,
1909-1940
M0008
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
0.5 Linear feet
Gunst, Morgan A.
Young, William Randolf Keltie
Scope and Content
Correspondence of William R. K. Young and Morgan A. Gunst with bookstores and societies selling rare and fine books. Much of the correspondence is with T. J. Cobden-Sanderson of the Doves Press.
Provenance
Gift of the estate of Morgan A. Gunst, 1959.
Access Restrictions
None.
- 25 typescript copies of letters from W.R.K. Young to T.J. Cobden-Sanderson between, December 8, 1911 and March 5, 1920. (Folder 1)
  Arrangement note
  Arranged chronologically.
- with typescript copies from T.J. Cobden-Sanderson to Young between, June 20, 1911 and April 2, 1920.; 28 ALS (Folder 2)
- 18 bills and receipts and 21 covers and 4 compliment sheets from the Doves Press to Young. (Folder 3)
- 8 press clippings about T.J. Cobden-Sanderson books and his death. (Folder 4)
- 1 LS, 2 receipts from Robert Cobden-Sanderson to Young. Letter 2 announcement lists for R. C.-S., dated Jan. 1, 1920. 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
- 32 typescript and autograph copies of letters from Young to the Societe des Amis du Livre Moderne. Most letters are to M. Charles Meunier and are dated from, June 4, 1909 to April 27, 1923. (Folder 6)
- 30 letters, mostly LS from the Amis du Livre in Paris to Young. Letters are dated from, Feb. 2, 1909 to July 30, 1923. (Folder 7)
- 8 receipts from the Amis du Livre to Young. (Folder 8)
- 26 book listings and information concerning the Amis du Livre Moderne. (Folder 9)
- Typescript copy of a letter from Young to Raphale Weill, written on Also a LS from Em. Terquem in Paris to John J. Newbergin, February 29, 1916. dated March 5, 1910. (Folder 10)
- 5 letters: 2 to Young from C-S; 1 to C-S from Young; 2 to Gunst from Millard. (Folder 11)
- 4 typescript copies of letters from Gunst to the Societe des Amis du Livre Moderne in Paris from, March 8, 1927 to March 5, 1928. (Folder 12)
- 10 letters from the Amis du Livre to Gunst, Also several receipts from the Societe to Young., dated March 7, 1917 to April 7, 1923. (Folder 13)
- 11 typescript letters and receipts from Young to Mrs. Alice Millard, March 24, 1927 to Feb. 4, 1937. (Folder 14)
- ca. 34 letters relating to the seizure of The Golden Asse of Apuleius by the US Customs. (Folder 15)
- 14 miscellaneous letters from Gunst to WRK Young, Melbert B. Cary, Jr., Paul Bonet, Rose Adler, G.A. Davidson, Jr. and Lucien L. Godschmidt. Letters dated from, May 7, 1918 to Aug. 6, 1940. (Folder 16)
- 18 letters from Rose Adler, Albert M. Bender, Paul Bonet, Bierre Beres Rare Books, Melbert Cary, Jr., Robert Cobden-Sanderson, Peter Fahey, Ernest Dawson of Dawson's Book Shop, Newbegin's Book Shop, and Nell U. O'Day. (Folder 17)
  Alphabetically arranged.
- 4 letters and 1 clipping re book lists. (Folder 18)
- Correspondence M. Young - Cobden-Sanderson (Folder 19)